Hi Guys welcome to planning process.
So even if you're the expert in anything you can not effectively executed.
If you don't have a plan because you'll get many challenges in real time and you need to have an effective
plan effective strategy in place to handle these real time challenges.
Therefore we should spend time on planning and in the context of project management.
All activities are planned.
Everything we have already gone through all this and knowledge areas.
So you have already seen that in all our knowledge areas.
We have a subjectivity for planning and all those activities are coming together in planning process
group.
So whether it was a risk management school management or a stakeholder management in all knowledge areas
we had planning all of them will be applied here.
They will come together as a unit in terms of sequential activities which you as a project manager is
expected to perform to create a comprehensive plan for all the activities you're going to perform in
the project.
So you don't have to leave anything out if you're going to perform.
Lexapro could management in this project you need to create that plan here and we are not executing
anything.
We are creating the plan.
So remember that.
So let's do.
When we say plan risk response we're not executing our fiscal.
We are simply planning a risk response and it's a very comprehensive process.
So in this slide you can see we only have two lines and it may create a sense that planning is very
limited but in fact take you to the next slide.
You can see all the activities are getting planned.
So we have to perform a lot of things a lot of planning for a successful project so we are going to
develop our project management plan.
We have to plan our school management.
We have to plan our requirement collections.
We need to define the school we need to create the Bluebeard's we need to define activities activities
we need to plan school management sequence activities as Tomate activity duration.
Could do our planned cost management estimate cost determined budget plan quality management plan to
source management estimate activity the resources plan communication management plan risk management
identify address perform qualitative risk analysis perform quantitative risk analysis plan go sponsors
plan procurement management plan stakeholder management so you can see that we have lifted plans subjectivities
plan processes from all the knowledge areas and there are additional activities.
Select Create oblivious.
You cannot have effective planning if you don't understand the work you are going to do.
So WB will help you by providing you information about the actual activities.
So on WB excretion is the process where you subdivide the work into smaller pieces so the smaller pieces
will provide information about not only the budget but it will also help you with requirement vomit
management their school management.
You can come up with a sequence of the activity which can later help you with school management.
You can identify any procurement if you need.
You can identify your communication management requirements and the risk associated with those work.
So when you start to plan a project you need to move step by step.
So let's how you get a one line problem statement that problem statement is further processed in initiating
process crew to produce a project charter and other documents.
You have seen in the last video now that project charter will help us drive it further.
So lets get back to our project charter and take it from there.
The first section here the present.
The problem is two months.
Let's quickly go through it.
ABC Corporation is looking to automate the correspondence process for the software application CD.
This is the application they already have.
Customer Service Agent use the system to process the new application but to mail the confirmation letter.
The man will print the letter and mail it to the customer so probably they export data from the system
manually or copy paste it and then use the printer to print those letters and mailer.
The current process is a manual control which acquires the processor to select the proper template and
manually copy the required information from CD.
So as you mentioned we are manually copying the information and as company usually has lot of templates.
It's again a big process for the operator to go through all these templates.
Select the appropriate one and then print it.
They will need to manually create an edit bill for each letter on FedEx us U.P.S. USPS for it's this
whole process takes two hours.
So at this stage our information is that this is the problem statement and then we have objectives what
should be done for the project.
We have high level requirements etc. so we have that information.
Now let's go back to our slide.
So we have requirements to plan a school.
We have high level requirements to plan our requirement collection which a business analyst will perform
to get functional the environment nonfunctional Klarman transitional requirements.
If I'm not sure about the business analysis side I have a course on business analysis you can use that
Pharmac management and business analysis in itself is very comprehensive activity.
So we'll basically include details about how we are going to gather our Marines their dates and things
like that.
So that information is used by a project manager to perform all of these activities.
For example we had high level requirements and we had high level budget requirements budgets and that
is going to help you with the school requirement collection schedule risk procurement if any needed.
So you will use that information to perform all of these activities.
And after completing your planning you need to get down with execution.
Therefore we are going to code execution process group in the next video.
Thank you.